<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Write-ups on b1d0ws</title>
    <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Write-ups on b1d0ws</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 15:30:50 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Road - TryHackMe</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/road-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 15:30:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/road-thm/</guid>
      <description>https://tryhackme.com/room/road
Recon and User Flag First, we do a nmap scan to discover that port 22 and 80 are open.
Visiting the website, there is a &amp;ldquo;Merchant Central&amp;rdquo; button that led us to an admin login page.
We can register our user.
After the login, we see just a normal dashboard.
In the &amp;ldquo;ResetUser&amp;rdquo; option, we see that we can alter our user password.
But what if we can alter the request to another user?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreaming - TryHackMe</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/dreaming-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 11:00:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/dreaming-thm/</guid>
      <description>https://tryhackme.com/room/dreaming
This machine was made by me and my friend Julio. Our Linkedin will be in the end of this write-up in case of any doubts or suggestions you guys have =).
Note: this write-up assumes that you know how the tools being used works and understand some basic concepts like reverse shells, since this is an intermediate CTF level.
Recon and Helm Flag First, we perform a nmap scan to discover what ports are open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netmon - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/netmon-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 14:30:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/netmon-htb/</guid>
      <description>https://app.hackthebox.com/machines/Netmon
Recon and User Flag First, we start with a nmap scan and discover that ports 21, 80, 139, 445 and 5985 are open.
Next, we perform nmap with default scripts and service detection flags on those ports.
As FTP is open, we connect to it with Anonymous login and see that we have an entire Windows Machine to explore in it. Going directly to the Public User we already get our user flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annie - TryHackMe</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/annie-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 13:38:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/annie-thm/</guid>
      <description>https://tryhackme.com/room/annie
User Flag First, I did the standard nmap scan and found that ports 22 and 7070 are open.
Next, I did an aggressive scan on these ports to find what service is behind it and found SSH on port 22 and probably an AnyDesk on port 7070, recognized by the &amp;ldquo;commonName=AnyDesk Client&amp;rdquo; snippet.
Searching for exploits in AnyDesk we see that there is an RCE vulnerability in anydesk 5.5.2. Although we do not know the version of anydesk, the attempt is valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biblioteca - TryHackMe</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/biblioteca-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:20:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/biblioteca-thm/</guid>
      <description>https://tryhackme.com/room/biblioteca
User Flag First, we start by enumerating the ports and services.
In the print below I have already set the ports to 22 and 8000 because I found out that they were open in a regular scan without any nmap flags.
I access the website and see that there is a login page. I try to create a user in the Sign-Up link to see what it looks like in there, but there is nothing interesting there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthem - TryHackMe</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/anthem-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:38:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/anthem-thm/</guid>
      <description>https://tryhackme.com/room/anthem
Website Analysis First of all, we run nmap and check which ports are open. As you can see, I ran a version scan with default scripts on the ports I found which were 80 (HTTP) and 3389 (RDP) to see if I could find anything interesting, but nothing turned up.
Next I checked the robots.txt file and found a possible password.
I also checked the disallowed entries and found a login page in /umbraco/, so we need to find our user since we already have the password!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>toc2 - TryHackMe</title>
      <link>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/toc2-thm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 10:45:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://b1d0ws.github.io/write-ups/toc2-thm/</guid>
      <description>https://tryhackme.com/room/toc2
User Flag First, we use nmap to see which ports are open.
We notice that ports 22 and 80 are open. Since we hardly have something to explore on SSH, we start by accessing the website.
Here we collect a username and password (cmsmuser:devpass) and maybe another possible username (Hunter).
One of the nmap scripts brought us an existing robots.txt entry, so let&amp;rsquo;s check it out.
Here we find the installation path for cmsms, which is the manager that should be installed in this application, and we also collect the name of the db to be used: cmsmsdb.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
